<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SelfMusing on Nihal</title>
    <link>https://nihalchoudhary.in/tags/selfmusing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SelfMusing on Nihal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nihalchoudhary.in/tags/selfmusing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reading as a Mirror</title>
      <link>https://nihalchoudhary.in/posts/2026/01/reading-as-a-mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nihalchoudhary.in/posts/2026/01/reading-as-a-mirror/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First post of 2026.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a long time, I avoided books. Not because I disliked learning itself but because books once felt like pressure, and authority to me. What I resisted was not reading but the condition under which it was imposed (and at the time, the material itself).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That shift happened when reading was no longer imposed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Non-fiction, in particular altered the way I see both the inner and outer world. Not by adding more information but by challenging the lens through which I perceive life. Slowly, it became clear that what we often call &lt;em&gt;“understanding”&lt;/em&gt; is nothing more than &lt;a href=&#34;https://nihalchoudhary.in/posts/2025/10/the-untouched-mind/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;conditioned thought&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; repeating itself in familiar patterns. And familiarity feels safe to the mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Untouched Mind</title>
      <link>https://nihalchoudhary.in/posts/2025/10/the-untouched-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nihalchoudhary.in/posts/2025/10/the-untouched-mind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately, something about kids is moving me. They carry an &lt;strong&gt;unconditioned mind&lt;/strong&gt;, a &lt;strong&gt;purity of consciousness&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If they’re angry, the anger is full.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;If they’re joyful, the joy is complete.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;If they’re curious, the curiosity has no end.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Their innocence isn’t something they learn, it’s what consciousness looks like before it’s shaped by beliefs, identity, conditioning, and inherited thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we grow, we accumulate layers of opinions, conditioning, expectations.&#xA;We stop seeing life directly and begin seeing it through a &lt;strong&gt;borrowed lens&lt;/strong&gt;.&#xA;The simplicity we were born with gets buried beneath thought, &lt;em&gt;mostly without our awareness&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Try</title>
      <link>https://nihalchoudhary.in/posts/2025/04/dont-try/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nihalchoudhary.in/posts/2025/04/dont-try/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The moment you resist, you go against the natural flow of existence. When you resist anything or anyone in its true nature, you unknowingly build a cage within the realm of existence and this is where you&amp;rsquo;ve already lost the game.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Freedom lies in the absence of resistance, and the mantra should be to &lt;em&gt;&amp;rsquo;not invest in resistance&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;. Solitude is found in experiencing the raw, being in tune with it rather than resisting its natural flow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Observer is the Observed</title>
      <link>https://nihalchoudhary.in/posts/2025/04/the-observer-is-the-observed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nihalchoudhary.in/posts/2025/04/the-observer-is-the-observed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People view the world through their own perceptions, and so they see nothing but &lt;em&gt;themselves&lt;/em&gt;. There exists one single universal consciousness, within which our minds create our own little distinct identities to perceive the universe on our own terms.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you become observant of your &lt;em&gt;self&lt;/em&gt; and the totality of life, you begin to see how everything is connected and that none of us are truly different. It&amp;rsquo;s all part of one system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I know that I know nothing</title>
      <link>https://nihalchoudhary.in/posts/2025/04/i-know-that-i-know-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nihalchoudhary.in/posts/2025/04/i-know-that-i-know-nothing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We unknowingly reject things due to the lack of our understanding of the broader reality they exist within. We must acknowledge the fact that we don&amp;rsquo;t even know the &lt;em&gt;knowns&lt;/em&gt;, let alone the &lt;em&gt;unknowns&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It makes sense why &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Socrates&#34;&gt;Socrates&lt;/a&gt; said:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;I know that I know nothing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
