<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nihal</title>
    <link>http://localhost:61167/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nihal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:61167/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reading as a Mirror</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61167/posts/2026/01/reading-as-a-mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61167/posts/2026/01/reading-as-a-mirror/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First post of 2026.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a long time, I avoided books. Not because I disliked learning itself but because books once felt like pressure, and authority to me. What I resisted was not reading but the condition under which it was imposed (and at the time, the material itself).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That shift happened when reading was no longer imposed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Non-fiction, in particular altered the way I see both the inner and outer world. Not by adding more information but by challenging the lens through which I perceive life. Slowly, it became clear that what we often call &lt;em&gt;“understanding”&lt;/em&gt; is nothing more than &lt;a href=&#34;https://nihalchoudhary.in/posts/2025/10/the-untouched-mind/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;conditioned thought&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; repeating itself in familiar patterns. And familiarity feels safe to the mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Untouched Mind</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61167/posts/2025/10/the-untouched-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61167/posts/2025/10/the-untouched-mind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately, something about kids is moving me. They carry an &lt;strong&gt;unconditioned mind&lt;/strong&gt;, a &lt;strong&gt;purity of consciousness&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If they’re angry, the anger is full.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;If they’re joyful, the joy is complete.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;If they’re curious, the curiosity has no end.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Their innocence isn’t something they learn, it’s what consciousness looks like before it’s shaped by beliefs, identity, conditioning, and inherited thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we grow, we accumulate layers of opinions, conditioning, expectations.&#xA;We stop seeing life directly and begin seeing it through a &lt;strong&gt;borrowed lens&lt;/strong&gt;.&#xA;The simplicity we were born with gets buried beneath thought, &lt;em&gt;mostly without our awareness&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Try</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61167/posts/2025/04/dont-try/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61167/posts/2025/04/dont-try/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The moment you resist, you go against the natural flow of existence. When you resist anything or anyone in its true nature, you unknowingly build a cage within the realm of existence and this is where you&amp;rsquo;ve already lost the game.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Freedom lies in the absence of resistance, and the mantra should be to &lt;em&gt;&amp;rsquo;not invest in resistance&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;. Solitude is found in experiencing the raw, being in tune with it rather than resisting its natural flow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Observer is the Observed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61167/posts/2025/04/the-observer-is-the-observed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61167/posts/2025/04/the-observer-is-the-observed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People view the world through their own perceptions, and so they see nothing but &lt;em&gt;themselves&lt;/em&gt;. There exists one single universal consciousness, within which our minds create our own little distinct identities to perceive the universe on our own terms.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you become observant of your &lt;em&gt;self&lt;/em&gt; and the totality of life, you begin to see how everything is connected and that none of us are truly different. It&amp;rsquo;s all part of one system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I know that I know nothing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61167/posts/2025/04/i-know-that-i-know-nothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61167/posts/2025/04/i-know-that-i-know-nothing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We unknowingly reject things due to the lack of our understanding of the broader reality they exist within. We must acknowledge the fact that we don&amp;rsquo;t even know the &lt;em&gt;knowns&lt;/em&gt;, let alone the &lt;em&gt;unknowns&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It makes sense why &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Socrates&#34;&gt;Socrates&lt;/a&gt; said:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;I know that I know nothing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:61167/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61167/books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My reading moves between philosophy, psychology, science, and fiction that reflects human experience.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;For a full and up-to-date list of what I’m reading and tracking, you can find me on Goodreads: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/iamnihal_&#34;&gt;Goodreads profile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing Github Actions to Serve a tool via Web</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61167/posts/2023/12/utilizing-github-actions-to-serve-a-tool-via-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 17:17:04 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61167/posts/2023/12/utilizing-github-actions-to-serve-a-tool-via-web/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR:&lt;/strong&gt; I employed GitHub Actions to execute a Go utility, essentially utilizing GitHub Actions as a server to serve my Go tool via a Web interface.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just for fun, I wanted to serve one of my Go tools &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/iamnihal/gh-archive&#34;&gt;gh-archive&lt;/a&gt; through a web interface. After some thought, I decided to make use of (or exploit) GitHub Actions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;strategy&#34;&gt;Strategy:&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gather user input through an HTML form (hosted via GitHub pages).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Trigger a dispatch event to create a workflow in GitHub with a unique name.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The GitHub Workflow will perform the tasks of building, running, and saving the output file of the Go program.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Retrieve the list of all workflow and iterate through the JSON results to match the workflow name.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Check the status of that workflow, if it&amp;rsquo;s completed or not.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If the workflow status is completed, retrieve the downloadable URL of the artifacts, download, and extract them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Display the content extracted from the output file back to the user.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To execute these steps, I skimmed through the GitHub REST API Documentation to identify the necessary APIs for the tasks at hand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:61167/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61167/projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;warf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/iamnihal/warf&#34;&gt;WARF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Tech Stack: Python,Django,JavaScript,Bootstrap,JQuery&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A dynamic Recon framework for web applications. Uncover vital details with subdomain enumeration, directory brute force, and endpoint gathering from Wayback URLs, JS files, and more. Highly customizable, it offers individual or full scans, organizing results in a powerful DataTable. Utilize its Dashboard for streamlined activity metrics, bringing all your targets together for efficient searching.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;apkrf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/iamnihal/apkrf&#34;&gt;ApkRF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Tech Stack: Python,Django,AJAX,Bootstrap&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ApkRF is a Reconnaissance Framework for APK files. It uses &lt;code&gt;apkleaks&lt;/code&gt; in the Back-end which decompiles the APK and look for interesting informations inside it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61167/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61167/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tinkering around with Computers and Web to understand why certain things work the way they work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Content Security Policy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61167/posts/2021/07/intro-to-content-security-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 19:00:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61167/posts/2021/07/intro-to-content-security-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Understanding certain web security concepts is crucial for comprehending how browsers, servers, and web applications function in specific scenarios. In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll provide a brief introduction to the Content Security Policy (CSP) mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &lt;figure class=&#34;image is-3by2&#34;&#xA;          &#xA;           data-align=&#34;center&#34; &gt;&#xA;    &lt;img alt=&#34;CSP Meme&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:61167/csp-meme_hu_70ebc6f2627565bc.jpeg&#34; /&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While inspecting the Request/Response cycle, you may have come across this HTTP Header in the response:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Content-Security-Policy: default-src &#39;self&#39;; script-src static.site.com&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, during web app development, you might have encountered this error in the browser console:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automate the Shit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:61167/posts/2019/04/automate-the-shit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 21:27:13 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:61167/posts/2019/04/automate-the-shit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this inaugural blog post, I want to share with you the magic of automation - a concept that can transform your daily tasks from mundane to marvelous.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Automation is the art of streamlining processes, reducing manual labor, and saving precious time. Why waste hours on repetitive chores when you can automate them effortlessly?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &#xA;  &lt;figure class=&#34;image is-3by2&#34;&#xA;          &#xA;           data-align=&#34;center&#34; &gt;&#xA;    &lt;img alt=&#34;can this be automated&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:61167/can-this-be_hu_9979e9ae97a8a1fb.jpg&#34; /&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;story&#34;&gt;Story&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;[UPDATE]: wallpaperplay.com is not functional anymore.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One fateful day, I found myself on a quest for minimalist wallpapers to adorn my Elementary OS desktop. My search led me to the promising trove of wallpapers at wallpaperplay.com. However, there was a caveat—the tedious download process:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
