<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nihal</title>
    <link>https://nihalchoudhary.in/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nihal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 17:17:04 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nihalchoudhary.in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing Github Actions to Serve a tool via Web</title>
      <link>https://nihalchoudhary.in/posts/2023/12/utilizing-github-actions-to-serve-a-tool-via-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 17:17:04 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nihalchoudhary.in/posts/2023/12/utilizing-github-actions-to-serve-a-tool-via-web/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: I employed GitHub Actions to execute a Go utility, essentially utilizing GitHub Actions as a server to serve my Go tool via a Web interface.&#xA;Just for fun, I wanted to serve one of my Go tools gh-archive through a web interface. After some thought, I decided to make use of (or exploit) GitHub Actions.&#xA;Strategy: Gather user input through an HTML form (hosted via GitHub pages). Trigger a dispatch event to create a workflow in GitHub with a unique name.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://nihalchoudhary.in/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nihalchoudhary.in/books/</guid>
      <description>Discover my current reads below, offering insights into philosophy, tech, and various topics I&amp;rsquo;m exploring. The Go Programming Language [Alan A. A. Donovan, Brian Kernighan] Sophie&amp;rsquo;s World [Jostein Gaarder] Meditations [Marcus Aurelius] Man&amp;rsquo;s Search For Meaning [Viktor Frankl] </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://nihalchoudhary.in/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nihalchoudhary.in/projects/</guid>
      <description>WARF Tech Stack: Python,Django,JavaScript,Bootstrap,JQuery&#xA;A dynamic Recon framework for web applications. Uncover vital details with subdomain enumeration, directory brute force, and endpoint gathering from Wayback URLs, JS files, and more. Highly customizable, it offers individual or full scans, organizing results in a powerful DataTable. Utilize its Dashboard for streamlined activity metrics, bringing all your targets together for efficient searching.&#xA;ApkRF Tech Stack: Python,Django,AJAX,Bootstrap&#xA;ApkRF is a Reconnaissance Framework for APK files.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://nihalchoudhary.in/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nihalchoudhary.in/about/</guid>
      <description>Tinkering around with Computers and Web to understand why certain things work the way they work.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Content Security Policy</title>
      <link>https://nihalchoudhary.in/posts/2021/07/intro-to-content-security-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 19:00:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nihalchoudhary.in/posts/2021/07/intro-to-content-security-policy/</guid>
      <description>Understanding certain web security concepts is crucial for comprehending how browsers, servers, and web applications function in specific scenarios. In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll provide a brief introduction to the Content Security Policy (CSP) mechanism.&#xA;While inspecting the Request/Response cycle, you may have come across this HTTP Header in the response:&#xA;Content-Security-Policy: default-src &#39;self&#39;; script-src static.site.com&#xA;Alternatively, during web app development, you might have encountered this error in the browser console:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automate the Shit</title>
      <link>https://nihalchoudhary.in/posts/2019/04/automate-the-shit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 21:27:13 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nihalchoudhary.in/posts/2019/04/automate-the-shit/</guid>
      <description>In this inaugural blog post, I want to share with you the magic of automation - a concept that can transform your daily tasks from mundane to marvelous.&#xA;Automation is the art of streamlining processes, reducing manual labor, and saving precious time. Why waste hours on repetitive chores when you can automate them effortlessly?&#xA;Story [UPDATE]: wallpaperplay.com is not functional anymore.&#xA;One fateful day, I found myself on a quest for minimalist wallpapers to adorn my Elementary OS desktop.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
