<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nihal</title>
    <link>https://example.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nihal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 19:00:42 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Content Security Policy</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/2021/07/intro-to-content-security-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 19:00:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/2021/07/intro-to-content-security-policy/</guid>
      <description>Understanding certain web security concepts is crucial for comprehending how browsers, servers, and web applications function in specific scenarios. In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll provide a brief introduction to the Content Security Policy (CSP) mechanism.
While inspecting the Request/Response cycle, you may have come across this HTTP Header in the response:
Content-Security-Policy: default-src &#39;self&#39;; script-src static.site.com
Alternatively, during web app development, you might have encountered this error in the browser console:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate the Shit</title>
      <link>https://example.com/posts/2019/04/automate-the-shit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 21:27:13 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/posts/2019/04/automate-the-shit/</guid>
      <description>In this inaugural blog post, I want to share with you the magic of automation - a concept that can transform your daily tasks from mundane to marvelous.
Automation is the art of streamlining processes, reducing manual labor, and saving precious time. Why waste hours on repetitive chores when you can automate them effortlessly?
Story [UPDATE]: wallpaperplay.com is not functional anymore.
One fateful day, I found myself on a quest for minimalist wallpapers to adorn my Elementary OS desktop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://example.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Tinkering around with Computers and Web to understand why certain things work the way they work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
